[Hello.]
[Let] us talk about
Let [us] talk about
Let us [talk] about
Let us talk [about]
[why] IT projects fail.
why [IT] projects fail.
why IT [projects] fail.
why IT projects [fail.]
[My] name is Alexei KLENIN.
My [name] is Alexei KLENIN.
My name [is] Alexei KLENIN.
My name is [Alexei] KLENIN.
My name is Alexei [KLENIN.]
[I] am a senior software developer
I [am] a senior software developer
I am [a] senior software developer
I am a [senior] software developer
I am a senior [software] developer
I am a senior software [developer]
[specializing] in Java and Node.js stacks,
specializing [in] Java and Node.js stacks,
specializing in [Java] and Node.js stacks,
specializing in Java [and] Node.js stacks,
specializing in Java and [Node.js] stacks,
specializing in Java and Node.js [stacks,]
[and] I have had
and [I] have had
and I [have] had
and I have [had]
[the]
[the] privilege of founding
the [privilege] of founding
the privilege [of] founding
the privilege of [founding]
[five] SaaS projects
five [SaaS] projects
five SaaS [projects]
[that] are currently online.
that [are] currently online.
that are [currently] online.
that are currently [online.]
[Did] you know that the
Did [you] know that the
Did you [know] that the
Did you know [that] the
Did you know that [the]
[cost] of IT project failures
cost [of] IT project failures
cost of [IT] project failures
cost of IT [project] failures
cost of IT project [failures]
[in] the US
in [the] US
in the [US]
[is] estimated to be
is [estimated] to be
is estimated [to] be
is estimated to [be]
[$2] billion annually?
$2 [billion] annually?
$2 billion [annually?]
[According] to Zipdo’s 2023 report,
According [to] Zipdo’s 2023 report,
According to [Zipdo’s] 2023 report,
According to Zipdo’s [2023] report,
According to Zipdo’s 2023 [report,]
[31.1%] of all IT projects
31.1% [of] all IT projects
31.1% of [all] IT projects
31.1% of all [IT] projects
31.1% of all IT [projects]
[are] canceled before completion,
are [canceled] before completion,
are canceled [before] completion,
are canceled before [completion,]
[52%] of them
52% [of] them
52% of [them]
[exceed] their initial budgets
exceed [their] initial budgets
exceed their [initial] budgets
exceed their initial [budgets]
[by] 189%,
by [189%,]
[and] only 16.2% of projects
and [only] 16.2% of projects
and only [16.2%] of projects
and only 16.2% [of] projects
and only 16.2% of [projects]
[are] completed on time
are [completed] on time
are completed [on] time
are completed on [time]
[and] within budget.
and [within] budget.
and within [budget.]
[Additionally,]
[the] Standish group CHAOS report
the [Standish] group CHAOS report
the Standish [group] CHAOS report
the Standish group [CHAOS] report
the Standish group CHAOS [report]
[report]
[tells] us that poorly built software
tells [us] that poorly built software
tells us [that] poorly built software
tells us that [poorly] built software
tells us that poorly [built] software
tells us that poorly built [software]
[has] five to six times
has [five] to six times
has five [to] six times
has five to [six] times
has five to six [times]
[higher] chances of failure
higher [chances] of failure
higher chances [of] failure
higher chances of [failure]
[due] to bad quality.
due [to] bad quality.
due to [bad] quality.
due to bad [quality.]
[The] consequences of such failures
The [consequences] of such failures
The consequences [of] such failures
The consequences of [such] failures
The consequences of such [failures]
[can] be catastrophic.
can [be] catastrophic.
can be [catastrophic.]
[Companies] suffer
Companies [suffer]
[financial] losses,
financial [losses,]
[a] tarnished reputation,
a [tarnished] reputation,
a tarnished [reputation,]
[missed] market opportunities,
missed [market] opportunities,
missed market [opportunities,]
[and] in 17% of cases,
and [in] 17% of cases,
and in [17%] of cases,
and in 17% [of] cases,
and in 17% of [cases,]
[the] failure of an IT project
the [failure] of an IT project
the failure [of] an IT project
the failure of [an] IT project
the failure of an [IT] project
the failure of an IT [project]
[leads] to the collapse
leads [to] the collapse
leads to [the] collapse
leads to the [collapse]
[of] the company itself.
of [the] company itself.
of the [company] itself.
of the company [itself.]
[Among] the top reasons
Among [the] top reasons
Among the [top] reasons
Among the top [reasons]
[for] these failures
for [these] failures
for these [failures]
[are] three critical mistakes,
are [three] critical mistakes,
are three [critical] mistakes,
are three critical [mistakes,]
[Unrealistic] expectations,
Unrealistic [expectations,]
[a] lack of proper technical documentation,
a [lack] of proper technical documentation,
a lack [of] proper technical documentation,
a lack of [proper] technical documentation,
a lack of proper [technical] documentation,
a lack of proper technical [documentation,]
[and] inadequate testing.
and [inadequate] testing.
and inadequate [testing.]
[The] good news
The [good] news
The good [news]
[is] that these mistakes
is [that] these mistakes
is that [these] mistakes
is that these [mistakes]
[are] entirely avoidable
are [entirely] avoidable
are entirely [avoidable]
[if] you partner with someone
if [you] partner with someone
if you [partner] with someone
if you partner [with] someone
if you partner with [someone]
[experienced] and competent.
experienced [and] competent.
experienced and [competent.]
[As] the founder
As [the] founder
As the [founder]
[of] an early stage project,
of [an] early stage project,
of an [early] stage project,
of an early [stage] project,
of an early stage [project,]
[you] can not afford
you [can] not afford
you can [not] afford
you can not [afford]
[to] make poor decisions
to [make] poor decisions
to make [poor] decisions
to make poor [decisions]
[at] the start.
at [the] start.
at the [start.]
[You] need to carefully
You [need] to carefully
You need [to] carefully
You need to [carefully]
[plan] the initial features
plan [the] initial features
plan the [initial] features
plan the initial [features]
[for] your MVP,
for [your] MVP,
for your [MVP,]
[choose] the right technical stack,
choose [the] right technical stack,
choose the [right] technical stack,
choose the right [technical] stack,
choose the right technical [stack,]
[and] find the most suitable
and [find] the most suitable
and find [the] most suitable
and find the [most] suitable
and find the most [suitable]
[cloud] solution.
cloud [solution.]
[These] foundational decisions
These [foundational] decisions
These foundational [decisions]
[are] crucial,
are [crucial,]
[and] for tasks like these,
and [for] tasks like these,
and for [tasks] like these,
and for tasks [like] these,
and for tasks like [these,]
[having] the right support
having [the] right support
having the [right] support
having the right [support]
[can] make all the difference.
can [make] all the difference.
can make [all] the difference.
can make all [the] difference.
can make all the [difference.]
[I] bring more than 10
I [bring] more than 10
I bring [more] than 10
I bring more [than] 10
I bring more than [10]
[years] of experience
years [of] experience
years of [experience]
[as] a senior software developer,
as [a] senior software developer,
as a [senior] software developer,
as a senior [software] developer,
as a senior software [developer,]
[lead] developer,
lead [developer,]
[and] founder of five
and [founder] of five
and founder [of] five
and founder of [five]
[SaaS] projects
SaaS [projects]
[that] are currently online.
that [are] currently online.
that are [currently] online.
that are currently [online.]
[For] an early stage startup founder,
For [an] early stage startup founder,
For an [early] stage startup founder,
For an early [stage] startup founder,
For an early stage [startup] founder,
For an early stage startup [founder,]
[having] access
having [access]
[to] this level of experience
to [this] level of experience
to this [level] of experience
to this level [of] experience
to this level of [experience]
[can] be extremely valuable.
can [be] extremely valuable.
can be [extremely] valuable.
can be extremely [valuable.]
[Do] not take unnecessary risks
Do [not] take unnecessary risks
Do not [take] unnecessary risks
Do not take [unnecessary] risks
Do not take unnecessary [risks]
[with] your project.
with [your] project.
with your [project.]
[Give] it the best
Give [it] the best
Give it [the] best
Give it the [best]
[possible] chance to succeed
possible [chance] to succeed
possible chance [to] succeed
possible chance to [succeed]
[by] partnering
by [partnering]
[with] a proven professional.
with [a] proven professional.
with a [proven] professional.
with a proven [professional.]
[If] success is your goal,
If [success] is your goal,
If success [is] your goal,
If success is [your] goal,
If success is your [goal,]
[investing] in experienced
investing [in] experienced
investing in [experienced]
[and] reliable expertise
and [reliable] expertise
and reliable [expertise]
[is] essential.
is [essential.]
[Schedule] a meeting now
Schedule [a] meeting now
Schedule a [meeting] now
Schedule a meeting [now]
[to] discuss your project,
to [discuss] your project,
to discuss [your] project,
to discuss your [project,]
[and] let us work together
and [let] us work together
and let [us] work together
and let us [work] together
and let us work [together]
[to] turn your ideas
to [turn] your ideas
to turn [your] ideas
to turn your [ideas]
[into] actionable
into [actionable]
[and] achievable steps.
and [achievable] steps.
and achievable [steps.]